See through another’s eyes, feel through another's heart,
and discover the meaning of brotherhood.
Brother Bear is a adventure, animation, family film directed by Aaron Blaise.
When an impulsive boy named Kenai is magically transformed into a bear, he must literally
walk in another's footsteps until he learns some valuable life lessons.
His courageous and often zany journey introduces him to a forest full of wildlife, including the
lovable bear cub Koda, hilarious moose Rutt and Tuke, woolly mammoths and rambunctious rams.
Kenai (voice), played by Joaquin Phoenix.
Koda (voice), played by Jeremy Suarez.
Denahi (voice), played by Jason Raize.
Rutt (voice), played by Rick Moranis.
Tuke (voice), played by Dave Thomas.
Sitka (voice), played by D. B. Sweeney.
Brother Bear is a 2003 American animated musical comedy-drama
film produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
It was directed by Aaron Blaise and Robert Walker, and written by Tab Murphy,
Lorne Cameron and David Hoselton, Steve Bencich and Ron J.
The film features the voices of Joaquin Phoenix, Jeremy Suarez,
Rick Moranis, Dave Thomas, Jason Raize, and D.
The story follows a Native American boy named Kenai who is transformed into
a bear by the Great Spirits as punishment for killing one.
To become human again, he must travel to a faraway mountain,
befriending a cub named Koda along the way.
Brother Bear premiered at the New Amsterdam Theatre on October 20, 2003, and was
released in the United States on November 1 by Walt Disney Pictures.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed
$250 million against a $46 million budget.
It received a nomination for Best Animated Feature at the 76th Academy Awards.
A direct-to-video sequel, Brother Bear 2, was released on August 29, 2006.
The film explores themes of friendship, sibling
relationship, transformation, grizzly bear, inuit.